# Jay Ferrier BSc(Hons)

07484 708895 | fezza\_j@btinternet.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jay-ferrier-5b5605278/

Portfolio: https://fezzaorfez.github.io/index.html

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a perceptive and driven Computer Science graduate, with an experience and interest in Software Engineering and Artificial Intelligence, as well as many years of programming experience in multiple languages and tools. I am looking for a graduate job in Software Engineering or Development. I have numerous work skills, such as teamwork and safety regulations, from work experience in the industry and part-time jobs.

#### **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

Nottingham Trent University |Computer Science| 2<sup>ND</sup> Class Honours-1<sup>ST</sup> Division (2.1 High)

#### Relevant Courses:

- Information and Database Engineering (High 1<sup>st</sup>)
- Final Year Project (Low 1st)
- Advanced Software Engineering (Low 1st)
- Systems Software (Low 1<sup>st</sup>)
- Advanced Analysis and Design (High 2.1)
- Advanced Artificial Intelligence (High 2.1)
- Software Design and Implementation (Mid 2.1)
- Service-Centric & Cloud Computing (Mid 2.1)

Invictus Sixth Form 2020-2022

- A Levels Computer Science
- A Levels Business Studies
- A Levels Maths

GCSE 2020

- GCSE Maths
- GCSE English
- GCSE Computer Science (Completed outside of school in my own time and at my own cost due to course removal)

# OCR Level 2 Diploma in IT User Skills (ITQ)

#### **SKILLS**

- Familiarity and passion of computer technology
- Coding Languages: C++, Python, C#, HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Java, Dart, Haskell
- Experience with:
  - Object Orientated Programming and APIs
  - Docker, Cloud technologies, and Nodejs
  - Databases, MariaDB, and MySQL
  - Git and Version Control

- o Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, and Android Studio
- First Aid Skills from Lifeguarding Certification
- Multiple successful leadership experiences from university group coursework
- Valid drivers licence and own transport
- Languages: English

### **Programming Projects**

# Final Year Project – Virtual Coach

- Virtual Powerlifting Coach for beginners of the sport.
- Developed using Human Pose Estimation, Artificial Intelligence and Software Development in Python with Tkinter

# • Client Group Project

- o Led a client group project developing statistics from a provided job database.
- o Developed in Python

#### Group Project – Smart Fridge

- Led a group project developing a mobile app for controlling a theoretical smart fridge for chefs and delivery stakeholders
- Developed in Android Studio with Flutter/Dart

#### Personal Project – Spotify Hands

- Project to control Spotify's Functionality through Hand Pose Estimation from a live webcam
- Developed with Python and Spotify API

#### Current Personal Paired Project – ClockIn

- Paired Programming Project to develop a mobile application for restaurants and pubs.
- Aides employees to track shifts, clock in and out of shifts, and see announcements and messages
- o Frontend developed in Flutter/Dart and Backend developed with Node.js and Cloud

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Simworx Itd | Work Experience

2019

- Week of work experience in motion simulation technology
  - Safety in the technology and engineering industry
  - Marketing and photo editing
  - Software and Hardware Engineering

# Round Oak | Kitchen Staff | Contact: Sean Weir, Round Oak Inn, Wombourne Aug 2019 to Aug 2022

Round Oak Inn in Wombourne.

- For the first two years:
  - Washing up plates, cutlery, etc.

- Helping chef staff by moving stock, processing stock ,etc.
- Help with food preparation.
- Cleaning
- For the third year:
  - o Promotion from pot washer to chef.
  - o Chef work, such as cooking food and setting up plates to be sent to customers.
  - Cleaning

#### Garden Maintenance Labourer | Contact: Andrew Ferrier, ADF Maintenance

June 2023 to August 2023,

May 2024 to September 2024

- Slab laying, Jet washing, Digging, Lawn mowing, Landscaping, Painting
- Communication with clients to ensure correct specifications of work and friendly relations.

#### TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

- Teamwork from working in a kitchen with other members of staff to ensure good customer service.
- Experience of working under pressure in a busy kitchen environment.
- Colleague communication skills from working in a kitchen environment with a restaurant team.
- Client communication skills from contact with garden maintenance jobs.
- Excellent work ethic from working within a busy restaurant environment.
- Teamwork skills from various group courseworks including the development of a mobile application for smart fridges

#### **INTERESTS**

Computer Science, Technology, Video Games, Snowsports, Formula 1, Powerlifting, Guitar and Music

#### **REFERENCES**

Sean Weir | Mr | Owner of the Round Oak Inn, Wombourne, Wolverhampton

Andrew Ferrier | Mr | ADF Maintenance